<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Values on Vulntology</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/</link><description>Recent content in Values on Vulntology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barrier Type</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/barrier-type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/barrier-type/</guid><description>Barrier Types There are multiple types of Barriers and each type has one or more subtypes which represent concepts more nuanced than their parent types.
Authentication/Authorization:
Impersonation: Encryption: Data or access to communication is protected through a mechanism that converts information into code or cipher. On Path: An adversary must position themselves inside a communication channel between two or more parties. This is usually accomplished by exploiting a trust mechanism and tricking both ends of the communication channel into believing that they are communicating with the intended party.</description></item><item><title>Context</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/context/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/context/</guid><description>Context Values The conceptual entity where the impacts are realized from successful exploitation of a security vulnerability. Different impacts can be realized by multiple contexts from multiple scenarios.
Values Application: A program designed and implemented to accomplish a specific task. Applications can run on or within operating systems, firmware or other applications. Container: A packaged set of software containing the necessary artifacts to execute in a container hosting environment, which is typically independent from a host operating system.</description></item><item><title>Criticality</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/criticality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/criticality/</guid><description>Criticality Values A measure of the relative importance of the associated Scope. This is most relevant when Scope has a value of Limited. When Scope is Limited, Criticality MUST be used in order to provide additional information about its importance. Alternatively, if Scope is Unlimited, Criticality SHOULD be considered as High. Criticality MUST be considered in concert with the Context to which it is associated. That is, for a given Context (such as Guest OS or Application), the Criticality should reflect how significant an associated impact could be for the specific Context.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Method</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/engineering-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/engineering-method/</guid><description>Engineering Method Values The method or mechanism used to manipulate a user into interacting with a malicious resource.
Values Malicious Application: An application that has been modified or crafted to perform operations that are unintended by the victim Malicious File: A file that has been crafted in a way that causes a target program to operate in an unintended fashion Malicious Link: A URL or hyperlink that has been crafted in a way that causes a target program or website to operate in an unintended fashion Malicious Website Content: A website that has been crafted in a way that causes a target program to operate in an unintended fashion or is used to simulate a site that the target user trusts.</description></item><item><title>Entity Role</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/entity-role/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/entity-role/</guid><description>Entity Role Values Describes the role an associated Context performs in the vulnerability scenario being described.
Values Security Authority: See CVSS v3.1 Section 2.2 for a full description of security authorities. Primary: Associated Context is the primary security authority of the vulnerability scenario. Secondary: Associated Context is a secondary security Authority of the vulnerability scenario. Component: See CVSS v3.0 Section 2.2 for a full description of security authorities. Vulnerable: Associated Context is considered to contain the vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>Exploited Weakness</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/exploited-weakness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/exploited-weakness/</guid><description>Exploited Weakness Values The weakness causing the Vulnerability. When choosing a value, the most applicable weakness should be selected.
Values The Common Weakness Enumeration (CWE) CWE which provides descriptions and names for various types of vulnerability weaknesses.
Examples CWE-79 CWE-399 Graph View</description></item><item><title>Impact Method Type</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/impact-method-type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/impact-method-type/</guid><description>Impact Method Type Values A description of the method used to exploit a vulnerability providing some additional information on the impact of exploitation. These are intended to be high level concepts that lead to more granular impacts as referenced in the logical and physical impact entities.
Values Items that are indented represent more specific values that can be used to describe the parent value. For instance, choosing Failure to Verify Content as a value would imply Trust Failure as well.</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/location/</guid><description>Location Values Designates the specific area or location impacted. Serves as supplemental information.
Values File System: The Logical Impact occurs within the file system Memory: The Logical Impact occurs within memory Network Traffic: The Logical Impact occurs within network traffic Graph View</description></item><item><title>Logical Impact</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/logical-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/logical-impact/</guid><description>Logical Impact Values A description of the possible impacts to a Context that a successful exploitation of the Vulnerability will have. The same Vulnerability can have multiple and different Logical Impact values across different Context or Scenario instances.
Values Items that are indented represent more specific values that can be used to describe the parent value. For instance, choosing Hang as a value would imply Service Interrupt as well.
Indirect Disclosure: The Vulnerability allows an adversary to learn information about the Context, but the knowledge gained is not from a direct read operation.</description></item><item><title>Physical Impact</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/physical-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/physical-impact/</guid><description>Physical Impact Values Used when exploitation of the Vulnerability could result in a tangible impact to a physical device, machinery, the surrounding environment, or people.
Values Items that are indented represent more specific values that can be used to describe the parent value. For instance, choosing Critical as a value would imply Human Injury as well.
Human Injury: An exploit of the Vulnerability could result in injury to users or nearby individuals.</description></item><item><title>Privilege Level</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/privilege-level/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/privilege-level/</guid><description>Privilege Level Values Abstraction to assist in capturing relative privilege levels. The abstraction is only for the sake of discussing the vulnerability and is not intended to communicate the actual granular privileges that exist in most information system environments. Privilege Level MUST be considered in concert with the Context to which it is relevant. That is, for a given Context (such as Guest OS or Application), the Privilege Level SHOULD reflect a reasonably appropriate mapping based on the security posture of the specific Context.</description></item><item><title>Resource Reference</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/resource-reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/resource-reference/</guid><description>Resource Reference Values Representation of a source of information. The source which provided the information related to the Vulnerability Scenario. This is typically in the form of a URL that leads to a webpage or document hosted over the world wide web.
Values A URL that assists in identification, explanation, or origin of the Vulnerability
Example https://nvd.nist.gov/ Graph View</description></item><item><title>Scope</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/scope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/scope/</guid><description>Scope Values A coarse measure of the level of impact an exploit could have on a target. In some cases, an impact has no constraints at all. An example of this is a vulnerability with a Read (Direct) Logical Impact association in which the adversary has access to the entire system, and thus has no constraints. In other cases, an Impact might have some constraints in place. An example of this would be a Write (Direct) Impact where the attacker is able to modify resources only accessible by the user.</description></item><item><title>Sector of Interest</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/sector-of-interest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/sector-of-interest/</guid><description>Sector of Interest Values Supplemental information identifying potential sectors of industry or use cases where the Vulnerability could have an impact.
Values Industrial Control Systems: The Vulnerability affects software that interfaces with manufacturing or production control systems. Health Care: The Vulnerability is found within information systems that are related to health care. This includes both software whose purpose is to provide services specifically for health care, as well as medical devices.</description></item><item><title>Theatre</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/theater/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/values/theater/</guid><description>Theatre Values The Theatre or Attack Theater is the area or place from which an attack must occur. Each separate theater represents varying levels of implied trust and attack surface.
Values Items that are indented represent more specific values that can be used to describe the parent value. For instance, choosing Internet as a value would imply Remote as well.
Remote: The exploit scenario requires that the attack occurs over the network stack; normally external to the target’s internal network such as from the Internet.</description></item></channel></rss>