<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Objects on Vulntology</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/</link><description>Recent content in Objects on Vulntology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Action</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/action/</guid><description>Action Object An Action is what occurs within a given Scenario. Actions involve a high level impact method which occur in a specific context. Actions can result in impacts to the context referenced. If multiple contexts are affected there will be multiple actions each relating to a given context.
Properties id (one): A globally unique identifier for the action that distinguishes it from other actions related to the same vulnerability. hasName (zero or one): A name or label to assist in identifying a given action in the context of the containing Vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>Barrier</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/barrier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/barrier/</guid><description>Barrier Object This could be any characteristic inherent in the vulnerability that could impede the adversary from achieving successful exploitation or a protection mechanism that may limit the actions or impact that can be taken even if the vulnerability is able to be exploited. These are often part of the system in which the product is deployed or are inherent in how the product is used.
Properties id (one): A globally unique identifier for the impact that distinguishes it from other impacts related to the same vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>Impact</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact/</guid><description>Impact Object An impact is a recognized result of an action taken for a given vulnerability scenario.
Semantics An impact is either logical or physical.
A logical impact is a virtual effect, resulting from an action, that affects information processed by a device or the operational state of a device that processes information.
Common examples include loss, disclosure, or corruption of information, or unexpected changes to the execution state of hardware or software.</description></item><item><title>Impact Method</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact-method/</guid><description>Impact Method Object A description of the method used to exploit a vulnerability providing some additional information on the impact of exploitation. These are intended to be high level concepts that lead to more granular impacts as referenced in the logical and physical impact entities.
Properties hasImpactMethodType (one): The nature of impact. See Impact Method Types.
hasGainedPrivilege (one - see notes): Abstraction to assist in capturing relative privilege levels. The abstraction is only for the sake of discussing the vulnerability and is not intended to communicate the actual granular privileges that exist in most information system environments.</description></item><item><title>Product</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/product/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/product/</guid><description>Product Object The software and/or hardware configurations that are known to be vulnerable to exploitation of the vulnerability Scenario. Different Product configurations can be associated with different Scenarios to allow for description of varying impacts and exploitation mechanisms.
Properties hasProductEnumeration (one or many): The enumeration of one or many products as dictated by the identification scheme. Contains a scheme and value pair. This is intended to be used for simple enumerations such as generic free text or common formats that identify explicit instances of products such as CPE or SWID.</description></item><item><title>Scenario</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/scenario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/scenario/</guid><description>Scenario Object A scenario describes the conditions surrounding the possible use of a vulnerability. A Vulnerability must have a least one Scenario, with multiple possible Scenarios being common. A single Vulnerability can likely be exploited by many different approaches with possible varying impacts. Multiple Scenarios can be used to describe these variations. For example, a remote exploit could rely on user interaction to be downloaded whilst a local attacker could use the same vulnerability to obtain the same or similar impact.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability/</guid><description>Vulnerability Object A Vulnerability is any weakness in the computational logic found in products or devices that could be exploited by a threat source.
Properties hasSectorOfInterest (zero or many): Supplemental information identifying potential sectors or use cases where the Vulnerability could have an impact. (See Sector of Interest) Relationships hasKnownChain (zero or many): Vulnerability Identifiers for other known Vulnerabilities that can be used in conjunction with the Vulnerability in question to achieve a different and likely greater impact hasIdentity (one or many): Vulnerability Identifiers may be associated with Vulnerability hasScenario (one or many): Scenarios shall be associated with Vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability Identifier</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability-identifier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability-identifier/</guid><description>Vulnerability Identifier Object Examples include a knowledge base article number, patch number, a bug tracking database identifier or a common identifier such as a Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) identifier. CVE is a widely adopted identifier used across many organizations.
Properties scheme (one): a namespace and/or scheme to identify the rules regading how a given Vulnerability identifier should be enumerated. value (one): The vulnerability ID based on the identification scheme. Relationships None.</description></item></channel></rss>