<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Objects on Vulntology</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/</link><description>Recent content in Objects on Vulntology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Action</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/action/</guid><description>Action Object An action is an activity resulting in an impact to an affected context, that occurs within a given scenario.
Semantics An action involves one or more high-level impact methods which occur in a specific affected context. Actions can result in impacts to the affected context. If multiple contexts are affected there will be multiple actions, with each action relating to a specific affected context.
Properties An action has the following properties.</description></item><item><title>Barrier</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/barrier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/barrier/</guid><description>Barrier Object A barrier can be any characteristic inherent in the vulnerability that could impede the adversary from achieving successful exploitation or a protection mechanism that may limit the actions or impact that can be taken even if the vulnerability is able to be exploited. These are often part of the system in which the product is deployed or are inherent in how the product is used.
Properties A barrier defines the following properties.</description></item><item><title>Impact</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact/</guid><description>Impact Object An impact is a recognized result of an action taken for a given vulnerability scenario.
Semantics An impact is either logical or physical.
A logical impact is a virtual effect, resulting from an action, that affects information processed by a device or the operational state of a device that processes information.
Common examples include loss, disclosure, or corruption of information, or unexpected changes to the execution state of hardware or software.</description></item><item><title>Impact Method</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/impact-method/</guid><description>Impact Method Object A description of the method used to exploit a vulnerability providing some additional information on the impact of exploitation. These are intended to be high level concepts that lead to more granular impacts as referenced in the logical and physical impact entities.
Properties An impact method has the following properties.
Type Name hasImpactMethodType
Cardinality one
Description The approach used to achieve an impact.
Based on the impact method&amp;rsquo;s type, some properties will be required when noted in the property.</description></item><item><title>Product</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/product/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/product/</guid><description>Product Object The software and/or hardware configurations that are known to be vulnerable to exploitation of the vulnerability scenario. Different Product configurations can be associated with different scenarios to allow for description of varying impacts and exploitation mechanisms.
Properties None.
Relationships A product has the following relationships.
A product object MUST include one of the following relationships:
hasProductEnumeration hasNvdCpeApplicabilityStatement hasCve5Product Product Enumeration Name hasProductEnumeration
Cardinality one
Description The enumeration of one or many products as dictated by the identification scheme.</description></item><item><title>Scenario</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/scenario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/scenario/</guid><description>Scenario Object A scenario describes the conditions surrounding the possible use of a vulnerability. A Vulnerability must have a least one Scenario, with multiple possible Scenarios being common. A single Vulnerability can likely be exploited by many different approaches with possible varying impacts. Multiple Scenarios can be used to describe these variations. For example, a remote exploit could rely on user interaction to be downloaded whilst a local attacker could use the same vulnerability to obtain the same or similar impact.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability/</guid><description>Vulnerability Object A Vulnerability is any weakness in the computational logic found in products or devices that could be exploited by a threat source NISTIR 7298.
Semantics A vulnerability affects a set of originating products and is described by a set of distinct exploitation scenarios. An originating product may be or contain the vulnerable product.
Each scenario is related to a set of affected products, which may be a subset of the originating products or may represent a product that depends on the originating product.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability Identifier</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability-identifier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/vulntology/specification/objects/vulnerability-identifier/</guid><description>Vulnerability Identifier Object Examples include a knowledge base article number, patch number, a bug tracking database identifier or a common identifier such as a Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) identifier. A CVE is a widely adopted identifier used across many organizations.
Properties A vulnerability identifier has the following properties.
Scheme Name scheme
Cardinality one
Description a namespace and/or scheme to identify the rules regarding how a given vulnerability identifier should be enumerated.</description></item></channel></rss>